or just do a full REX yeah just make you
know default please like yeah if you
can't write Rex you need to go fix
[Music]
that sup y'all before we hop into this
episode I just wanted to remind you that
we launched the critical thinking
Discord Community a couple weeks back
and ever since we did it's been pretty
much a constant stream of hacking
stories exploitation techniques cool
research tool devs in there talking
about features and taking feature
requests um so it it's been a really
great Community I've personally learned
a lot already and I think you will too
so definitely check that out if you
haven't already it's at ctbb doow
Discord um and for those of you that are
interested in supporting the podcast you
can become a subscriber on Discord uh
there's a $
2510 and $5 uh subscription which gives
you access to various benefits ranging
from private scripts and uh unredacted
bug reports and uh what else master
classes uh that that would be at the
critical thinker tier the top tier all
the way down to a supporter badge at the
lowest tier um so if you're interested
in supporting the pod that's the best
way to do it all right all right with
that ctbb doow Discord I'll see you
there enjoy the
episode yo sup dude yo yo how's it going
good just got done with my uh nice
little pre- podcast little bounce little
warmup ready to you seem to always
forget that you're three hours ahead of
me yeah yeah it's like 7:15 in the
morning for you right now yeah yeah
something like that rip well thanks for
getting up early to record the Pod um I
wanted to start today off with a little
bug
Bounty struggle story you know because I
feel like a lot of the people that
listen to this
pod you know I I hear a lot of or at
least what we see on the Discord often
is you know people saying there's a lot
of struggles to bug Bounty and that and
that's true but it seems like you know
everyone's just sort of at the top
winning winning winning you know posting
there I just got awarded whatever bounty
on whatever on Twitter right but I
wanted to flip it around a little bit
today and give you guys a little of an
insight into the actual hacking
struggles um
so this this goes back to I guess the
past two live hacking events that I've
been a part of the one in Tokyo and the
one in in Portugal and um so I just
barely scraped into the top 10 in in uh
Tokyo which is great that was my goal um
but and I think I placed like fourth or
fifth in in Portugal
but both of those events for me were
like a little
bit subpar as far as like bounties go
right as far as like actual earnings go
and and even though you know I was
ranking pretty well on him it was a
little bit little bit rough and so and
and around this time you know I'm
traveling all around Japan I'm traveling
all around Portugal and I get back to my
home and I'm like man I feel so
disconnected from the hacking you know
like I haven't had like a normal
schedule where I've deep dived something
in a long time um and I just feel like
that start you know that difficulty
getting restarted again do you know what
I'm talking about I mean you're you're
pretty like I feel like you do hunting
in spurts right do do you also feel that
sort of like stress when you haven't
been hacking in a while and you have to
restart yeah I mean I feel that a lot
like I don't hack nearly as much as you
do um and so like that is kind of like
an all the- time struggle for me where
like if I have stopped hacking for a
while and I need to get back in into it
it's very difficult for me to like get
that ball rolling again usually I either
need um somebody who I'm like hacking
with who like has the energy going
already like you're usually a good
source of that um or I'll have to like
just you know kind of like anything else
that's really difficult you just have to
like start on it like how do you eat an
elephant one bite at a time so it's the
same thing with any other hard task
that's like difficult to start you just
have to start it and eventually like
you'll get into it and usually like
especially cuz it's something that we
enjoy like to Flow State or something
but um you really just have to start and
that that's always like the hardest
thing is just like starting with no sort
of like you
know yeah exactly and that's that's kind
of where I was at this time man and like
this one actually really was hard for me
to push through like normally it's not
very hard for me to push through and
normally I'll just be like you know all
right time to just get back at it but
this time I was like man I just I don't
know what Target to go after I don't
know what like I was just kind of lost
you know um but just like you said you
know you just kind of you pick a Target
and you and you deep dive it and then
here's the thing man here's the thing
that was crazy I went four days which is
like not super irregular for me but I
was feeling it a little you know I was
feeling the pressure a little bit I went
four days without finding a bug right
zero bugs for four days and that like
you know when you're already feeling
down in the dumps and you're like you're
already feeling that the that
the ambition is not there that the
motivation is not there that just you
know it's like like a knife in the chest
and twist it you know I will say this is
like normal for me cuz like often times
when I look at programs I'll be looking
at like a lot of times mobile stuff and
yeah for lots of programs there's not
mobile bugs like it's just like either a
very small app or it's just like you
know small attack surface whatever and
like I'll spend like a day like a whole
day just like digging looking at all the
different things like following paths
down rabbit holes that don't lead
anywhere and then just like by the end
of it I'm like okay well I I know a
little bit more more than I did earlier
but that's about it yeah and and and but
you know that's that's the way you got
to start right like that's the way you
got to get into it because
yeah and I don't know so like after
those four days I was like man I feel
like [__] but it's Friday and I'm gonna
give it because I this is a full hacking
week like I did you know nine to five um
you know for this week trying to get
back into the schedule of things and
stuff like that and then on the last day
I popped like three bugs in a crit you
know they P out right before this call
so I'm very very hyped about that AES um
uh but you know that it takes a little
while to get back into your groove and
that's one of the things that I that I
see people that are beginners I mean I
mean obviously even Pros struggle with
it right you know because we're having
this conversation right now but um this
is one of the things I see almost all
hackers struggle with actually is is
this whole concept of like okay how much
time do I devote into this how do I get
restarted when I'm not you know already
in the zone how do I get back back in
that flow State and dude I mean it's I
would I'm going to like come back and
listen to this next time I'm in this
same situation so I can give myself a
little pep talk just start and just
start doing it and start hacking and
start gaining expertise on an
application and dude the the vs will
come so now I'm back I'm back on my
groove and and I think one of the things
I I think for me um one of the pros that
I haven't really talked about much on
the podcast about being a full-time bug
Bounty Hunter is that you actually don't
have to deal with this very often
because you you know you often have a
pipeline of bugs you're hacking on a
really regular basis and you know unless
you're taking massive amounts of time
off you very rarely have to like redo
that whole process again so that that's
that's something I'm really grateful for
yeah I was going to say like notes are
also like one of the biggest things that
you can use to help yourself because
often times if you think about it like
when you're hacking 9 to5 um like every
day a week every day of the week you
know you come back you know what you
were doing yesterday um like you it's
fresh in your mind you know at most it's
maybe 10 hours 12 hours old and you know
if you come back to that you you know
what you were working on but if you go
away for like a week A lot of times like
your memory then gets filled with other
things that you were doing like you kind
of start to forget about the like
recency of the specifics of the details
of things that you were looking into so
if you take notes of those things like
everything that you're working on like
all the things that you were looking
down all the things that you like wanted
to still investigate and then you come
back to it like that can help offet that
um that like delay of like not knowing
where to start and what things to look
at because you have a list of things
that you know you were already looking
at and you can sort of Kickstart that
the other thing is um like you just have
to remember that anytime you start a new
program it's always going to be like
this so we have the same yeah problem
when we start like any new program
there's always that Discovery period in
the beginning and it just takes time to
like get familiar with the program like
spend time susing it out understanding
the ins and outs if you've taken time
off and switched programs then like
that's you know double whammy right so
you have no context on this new program
you still have to do Discovery phase and
you're trying to kickart yourself with
no notes no starting point no nothing
like yeah it's definitely going to be a
little bit of a slow roll but once you
can get there you know take notes on
everything that's like looks interesting
so that way when you come back like even
if you take two days off you can come
back again you have notes stuff to look
at yeah no that that's that's a great
Insight dude and I actually it's funny
you mention that without even knowing it
because I actually had been tuning up
you know my notes game because we we
talk about it on the Pod a decent bit
and we've seen an overwhelming
representation of the the no notes sort
of people right um but ever since that
happened I was like man there's got to
be people that take notes on you know on
a pretty regular basis so I've been I've
been finding them and I'm going to have
them on the Pod um and we're going to be
able to interview them about their their
note-taking things but um one of the
things that I've noticed that's pretty
consistent um across the takers is they
are
very consistent top performers on one
program right you don't see a lot of
people that switch programs on a regular
basis taking very detailed notes but the
people that do take notes they stick to
one program and they absolutely crush it
and they know the insides and outs of
that program like they are the person
for that program right um so that was
really inspiring to me and and I started
to so I'm going to look at my notes
right here I've got a section that says
almost vules gadgets okay that those are
the things that are sort of like um uh
you know almost there that maybe I might
be able to use in a chain I've got app
segments which is actually like on the
Target that I'm I'm talking about it's
one big domain but there's lots of
different like sub apps under different
paths right that have different JS files
are clearly different you know um
segments of the app and knowing about
each one of those you know you can try
to chain together pieces from all the
different ones to to build gadgets and
then I've just kind of got interesting
functionality and notes on on the actual
Deep dive and then specific Target
specific notes um well I can tell that
you've already done some of that
Discovery phase too because those things
that you mentioned even even just like
that subp concept it shows that like
yeah you spend time looking at this you
realize that there was some sort of a
pattern here and eventually like you
sort of cracked it in a sense that makes
sense at least for now like a lot of a
lot of the time like while we're doing
this stuff I think it's kind of like
running theories where like you don't
really know 100% what's going on but
like you can take a pretty good guess
based on the behavior you see and so a
lot of times it's good to make those
sort of assumptions where you say okay
I'm pretty sure this is how this is
working I'm going to run with this
Theory until I run into some data that
you know contradicts my my theory and
then I can rework my theory if I need to
and that can let you you know find
vulnerabilities because if you if you
have a good idea of how it's working in
the back end or like what it's actually
doing then you can you know make more
educated guesses towards the type of
bugs that you're targeting the types of
techniques that you're trying um and so
I I like that sort of like running
Theory type stuff where basically you
have you know oh there's sub apps here
okay you know I'm going to run with that
theory until I see something that
contradicts it or maybe there's like two
different systems here and that leads
you down and it also helps you like
identify like anomalies within those
patterns so that if something does
contradict your theory you're like huh
that's weird like why what is that like
why does that behave
differently yeah no 100% And that this
same sort of thing you know France was
talking about on the episode um you know
with him about about mapping out what's
going to be happening in your head and I
think taking notes on that is uh is a
really big um yeah it's a really big
benefit and and actually so taking the
notes thing a little bit further um I
need to get a couple of these people on
but one of the things that i' I've
noticed in particular that people um who
really crush it on one program have been
taking notes on is um ooth stuff um you
know uh enumerating different client IDs
uh enumerating different Scopes
associated with different um you know
apps uh trying to get client secrets
that sort of thing right um and and very
very cool because using those things we
can start to really map out and really
understand at a deep level and man do
they understand it at a deep level how
the permissioning works for a given app
and so I just started diving that a
little bit deeper and I already found a
crit like less than a week in um with it
uh and and as I'm as we're recording
this episode I'm seeing notifications
pop on my phone like okay yep we're
dealing with it we're dealing with it
now um so that's that's that's always
good to see um and so yeah especially
off based notes I think really really
important yeah I mean off stuff is
always like really weird um because the
more complex that an organization is
oftentimes there's multiple spots where
you'll log in and uh the the behaviors
of those off systems either they have to
be centralized which means that they
have some sort of like aoth mechanism or
like a centralized off system or they're
implemented separately which means that
there needs to be consistency across
multiple imp implementations and so in
both cases there's rooms for error and
there's rooms for for holes and stuff so
I we actually have some some running
notes in a in a separate document so I
think we'll uh we're gonna have an aath
episode soon I don't know if it'll be
today though I don't think it's today
yeah I it's on the episode for today
dude we have so much stuff to cover and
we're already you know as far in as we
have and we haven't even covered the
first bullet point so um yeah no we'll
definitely have an episode on that I
feel like I need to Deep dive it a
little bit more before we get the
episode on it though but I will say Joel
I don't know if you went back listened
to the saml episode that I released last
week um I know you've been all over the
place I think you're recording in a
hotel right now but um yeah that that
that sort of thing um you know will also
apply a lot a lot to the ooth and and
open ID stuff um so definitely gonna
excited to keep deeping that yeah
absolutely um all right dude we launched
the Discord man we did the disc it's out
there what are your thoughts it's been
really crazy um we're up to almost a
thousand members now I just checked this
morning it's like yeah you know almost a
thousand um and uh yeah it's really
awesome to see just like all the people
coming in having conversations like
every day there's just hacking
conversations just random things um
people posting research and tools and
hey I found this thing hey anybody got
an idea about this it's it's really
awesome to see um the community like you
know communicating and working on plugs
together and and just like you know
enjoying this space so yeah already just
one weekend it's really an amazing or
two weeks in one week yeah I was I was
so so excited and uh encouraged by how
much of a response we've had from the
community and how active all the
channels are um and yeah and also just
big shout out to anyone who got in on
the the um subscriptions the Discord
subscription memberships early on um
that is like so exciting for us to see
and uh very exciting for our wallets as
well because we've been run running
critical thinking at like what like $500
$600 burn rate per month ever since the
beginning pretty much so um getting some
some income to offset that is really
really helpful for so for those of you
that want to support the Pod definitely
go check out the Discord Subs um and
we're dropping a bunch of really cool
stuff in the uh exclusive subscribers
Channel U mostly in the in the uh the
critical thinkers critical thinkers
Channel um definitely like it's not just
like for supporting the Pod like
obviously we appreciate the support but
it's also for you guys um you know it's
really for sharing exclusive information
and stuff we posted a bunch of different
um exclusive techniques and tips and
links and tools and all sorts of things
in the in the critical thinkers chat um
we're working on setting up our first
Master Class we've got some AMA
questions coming in so yeah there's a
lot of really awesome awesome things
that are available in those in the paid
tiers that are more exclusive benefits
um but just in general like there's tons
of people who just come in chat in the
general chat hacking the the hacking
chat it's really it's really awesome
yeah I mean we've definitely had some
more I think the discussions that happen
in the the supporter chats you know
they're they're uh a lot of them are
tailored to specific vulnerabilities and
and stuff you want to keep in the you
know more exclusive channels but there's
been a lot of great um high quality
stuff like you mentioned in the general
and hacking channels as well and uh so I
just grabbed a couple of the things that
I wanted to kind of just give you guys a
taste of what we're seeing in the
Discord um the first thing was we're
seeing a lot of conversation and really
helpful conversation actually
surrounding JS monitoring um and and I'm
a little I'm not going to lie Joel I'm a
little like I'm a little sad actually to
see so many people do this because like
I feel like you
know content Creation in the bug Bounty
realm is a little bit tricky uh because
it's like okay you know do what do I
share and how much do I share right and
then when I share how much competition
am I creating for myself right and I
will say I have noticed an increase in
dupes since we started doing critical
thinking I I really have um and and
stuff that you wouldn't really think is
a dupe either and and you know it could
just be my my you know bias or whatever
but um uh you know I guess it there when
there are people actually taking the
advice it's it's a little bit you know
and people talking about it in the chat
like oh you know I set up this script um
you know I'm monitoring this endpoint
and I already found these bugs I'm like
all right well there goes one of my you
know it's true because like literally
just the other day somebody in the in
the critical thinkers chat they pinged
us and they were like yeah you know like
I I was stuck on this bug and like then
I was listening to the episode and you
guys mentioned this thing and I tried it
and it worked and like you know I
wouldn't have even thought about that I
was like oh man like yeah and it's great
it's great to see but also you know it
it does it's that it's that dichotomy
you know it's that it's that battle uh
that you have as a content creator Buck
Bounty but needless to say we're glad to
see it we're going to keep them coming
for yall um because you know when the
community continues to perform bug
Bounty industry continues to perform and
you know a rising tide lifts all boats
is that it that is it saying yeah that
is the expression man I got
it there's a mental there's a whole like
psych psychology thing behind this
between like um yeah uh there's like two
mentalities where it's like finite
mentality and like I don't know what the
other one is but it's basically like it
infinite game mentality is that
basically think it all is one pie it
when somebody gets added is it does
everybody get a smaller slice of the pie
or does the pie increase um and like
usually like people individually like
have like a sort of a set like view on
this um about like how they think about
things just in general and it's like the
same thing with bug Bounty where it's
like you know if I share data like am I
taking away from my bounties or am I
just like increasing the overall
research and then everybody gets more
bounties Etc yeah and to and to be
honest man everyone's got such unique
perspective when it comes to what kind
of bugs they're going to find as well
it's very unlikely that that I am
actually causing dupes for myself but I
will you know I think we mentioned the
one time when we had Alex Chapman on the
Pod there was one one occasion when uh a
Blog that Alex wrote really helped me in
exploiting a bug that he duped on uh and
and I that just uh in that moment I was
like man I feel for you brother
that's so funny yeah um the things I
wanted to shout out in particular were a
couple of the people on the Discord um
xnl hacker who you guys probably know
we've shouted him out Lots um for the
tools he's making is um is using a
modified version of a tool called
JSM um which is a uh exactly what it
sounds like a sort of jobs change
monitor for bug Bounty um we got another
person in there Abby who is using a
custom script uh and using the
scrappy uh python Library to reach out
and do the JavaScript monitoring which
is actually very close to what I do and
he writes a custom script for each
individual um uh company that he's
monitoring you know tailored to that
company's JS files and you know running
red jaxes that will produce results on
that company's JS files and then um
there's a couple other people I I'm not
even going to try to pronounce e
timeus uh and then static flow as well
is also might be building something for
the people I don't know I don't know if
static flow is ready to uh you announc
that yet but we've been having some uh
exciting Chats on a secret channel in
the Discord so uh Tanner whenever you're
ready to drop that thing man you know
the world might be ready for it so yeah
absolutely no we've been um we've been
working behind the scenes with Tanner on
static flow on some uh some cool stuff
so we're hoping again more some
exclusive stuff so if you're interested
you know go check out the Discord but um
yeah we're we're hoping to have some ex
more exclusive critical thinking tool
and all sorts of fun things coming up
very soon yeah dude this the the swag
game should be fun too coming up we're
we're working on that I don't know what
the timeline like is that going to be
because I was like yeah I was talking to
our our person who's kind of helping
with that and I was like hey you know
you think we could roll this out by
Christmas and they're like no it's like
late November it's like yeah can we do
this in a month during the busiest
season not a
chance so yeah no that makes sense um
yeah okay so obviously uh couple more
things I mentioned in the Discord was uh
secondary context bugs which we've
talked about on the PO a decent bit I'll
mostly skip over this now but I I am
glad to see people saying hey I'm
actually finding secondary context bugs
out here that have high impact um and
and actually I know of a couple people
that haven't even posted in the Discord
publicly but I've dm'd me privately
saying hey found some cool secondary
contact bugs and scored massive massive
bounties from it yeah secondary contact
bugs are are really really really
interesting we talked about it a bunch
so if you're interested you can check
out um a good example Sam Curry's uh
Starbucks uh blog yeah Sam Curry and
Rino Raider featuring Rhino Raider yeah
oh that guy who's that goodness Joel
what the heck man I it's on Sam curry.
net I don't know what to tell you it's
dude well it's Sam curry [__] you know
it it really is there's there's a
specific brand of stuff and that same
curry [__] right there um but yeah sorry
I need to get some water but the uh the
last thing was like there's been some
really
good automist automist this is a new
automation [__] yeah in um in the
Discord we've talked a good bit about um
DNS Wild Card filter and I'll just kind
of give the tldr of that here
um a lot of people have a lot of
different approaches some tools do it
automatically I think dnsx does some
stuff um but really it's kind of a hard
problem to nail down and one of the
approaches that seems to have worked
best for me and I've kind of discussed a
little bit with the community is this
concept of wild card profiles and um
what you'll do is when you when you
detect a wild card um when you're doing
subdomain enumeration um you you will
take that wild card and put it through a
process to create a profile for what
this specific Wild Card looks like so
you're generating multiple um iterations
you're resolving it multiple times
you're quering different resolvers
you're adding and prepending things you
know trying to figure out exactly where
the uh Wild Card break is um in the in
the uh definition uh you know where it
is at uh in the subdomain structure that
sort of thing and then you're also
resolving it multiple times with
multiple resolvers to try to get um an
idea of what IPS are being round robin
returned in that in that and then
creating a a profile of sorts uh for
what that wild card should look like and
then when you resolve things which match
that wild card um in the subdomain level
but do not match that response then you
know you've got a diamond in the rough
something that most people other people
won't find because they're just going to
be saying all right everything under dot
whatever is is a is a wild card um and
I'm just going to ignore it but this one
isn't and so um there's a lot of really
good scope living in those sort of uh in
those sort of caveats if you can read
between the lines for the DNS yeah for
sure and um an interesting thing about
wild cards so I'm pretty sure this is
like all the time um but basically like
the way that you configure a wild card
on DNS is that your your a record
essentially the the the record itself is
is an asterisk it's a star and so you
can you can do a lookup on that if you
think something's a wild card and you
want to verify you can actually just dig
star. whatever.com no you cannot yes you
can yep and it actually yeah yeah
totally what the freak Joel
yeah hold up hold up hold up
no hold on hold hold on I I gotta I
gotta
what well I mean okay I guess that sort
of makes sense because anything there I
mean what can I do a slash there like oh
yeah okay but any character is going to
return that though right right but
typically like a DNS like because that's
the way that it's being configured like
yes the wild card is probably wild
carding itself maybe but yeah um that's
also a really easy way that you can
concretely check um I wonder wild I
wonder if some authoritative name
servers will
actually result like give you more
information uh if you actually hit star.
whatever
do.com rather than you know blahy blah.
whatever.com that's very interesting I I
didn't know interesting behavior um yeah
because like I can I have some wild
cards configured on my own domain and I
do it's B it's configured like that like
you do an asterisk do whatever and you
can you know look it up and I'm not sure
if it's that the wild card is wild
carding itself or if that's that that
you know it's wild carding everything
else and it's giving you the literal
lookup but um either way like that's a
really good way that you can get
basically the Wild Card response and
then you can use that to filter it so if
you're not sure that something's a wild
card you can literally just start out
yeah very nice dude I didn't know that
that's definitely something to to keep
in in mind and you know we've been kind
of scheming with some of the guys in
there with golden and them um you know
about how exactly to get this stuff to
work and you have to put together so
many different um different pieces of
the puzzle um uh when when trying to do
this effectively uh and we even seeing
some experts hop in there like uh like
Sean uh s we we'll hop in there um yeah
from M note and and give some some good
stuff so I really appr appreciate um the
guests also being active in the in the
Discord that's uh that's really
encouraging to see yeah it was hilarious
on the first day he he was like what's
happening I just woke up and my phone is
exploding I have like a million
notifications from this Discord to sleep
there was 15 people in here I woke up
there's 500 people in here yeah dude we
we um we probably should have let them
know but we had all the guests join the
Discord in advance because we were using
it for like logistic stuff with planning
and that sort of thing um and then you
know we didn't tell anyone you're going
to launch it and then all of a sudden
ding ding ding ding D ding ding you know
like the the welcome you know channel is
like blowing up um so if you're
listening sorry about that Sean hope you
hope you get some sleep sorry for anyone
on the uh you know Asia time zone when
we launched that uh but yeah yeah um
cool there was a there was another tool
that I saw posted in there um it's
called thank you next um yeah and and
this is this seems specifically for next
Jaz so I I believe nextjs is mostly used
for web three applications um but it
might be used for other things but um
it's called thank you next letter you
like next thank you nextjs um basically
all it does is it just parses it looks
for a nextjs build manifest and then it
will parse out all of the uh all the
routes that are available through that
uh through the nextjs build manifest and
it'll just print them out for you super
easy um so if you're looking at nextjs
applications you see it's using nextjs
you can just run it through this tool
it'll give you all the routes um super
easy nice
cool piece of research dudee I love this
I really I love this a lot and actually
this is something very um sort of
related to something that I wanted to
talk about on the Pod today which was
this this concept of client side paths
and and when we think about JS um when
we think about JS
file uh Recon you know reading the JS
files trying to extract the end points
that sort of thing we kind of think
about this like you know grit your teeth
process of staring at the JS and like
till your eyes bleed and like trying to
trace back all these functions to like
um you know get the correct parameters
for a request that's going to be sent to
the server side API but in reality
something that I've been sleeping on is
this whole concept of looking at how the
client side routing actually works
because like nine times out of 10 the
applications that you're dealing with
nowadays are going to all return the
same you know you're going to hit SL
blahy blah and it's still going to
return the same response and then the js
on the client side you know angular
react nextjs or whatever is going to
look at the path and show you a page
based off of that right right um and so
looking at these these client side paths
as well within the JS files is massively
helpful because not only can you trigger
you know various functions that are
bound to these routes um uh and maybe
even get xss I've popped several xss
over the past week because of this trick
um uh but you can also um not have to
like go through this terrible process of
trying to figure out like you know what
parameters go where in a request and
actually just have that the app
generated for you by forcing a specific
state in the application by navigating
to that route and I just I don't know
why I haven't been doing this more often
and it's just it's a great trick well
and another thing that I've noticed is
that um especially with webpack stuff so
a lot of times you'll still have the
webpack uh map files and you can unmap
it you can view it in your browser um or
you can unmap it locally and oftentimes
what you'll see is that the pages there
there's usually a folder called like
pages and it has like the the jsx or
whatever uh the is that the
right terminology the like tempting
thing no no no like like the TS TSX
files typescripts and then jsx I think
probably for just straight JavaScript
stuff yeah right right so basically
those like htmls JavaScript templating
type of stuff that's used in react
typically um and you'll see that it'll
only return like one page and a lot of
the time that's because it's using
either um uh lazy loaded JavaScript or
because it's explicitly like checking
whether or not it should load other
parts of the app even though it's in the
code and you just have to do a little
bit more digging and and the page like
IDs and stuff are in there so just like
what you're talking about where
essentially like all the stuff is on the
client it already like the the front end
Pages like there might be backend API
endpoints that it's hitting and those
will also be in the JavaScript but
really the available Pages for you to
browse are all within that file right
there and so you can look through and
you can find them and you can pull them
out and then usually you can also go one
step further and you can either get the
lazy loaded file for that page or you
can find maybe there's a specific JS
file just loaded on that page and that
has extra functions extra HT extra API
endpoints all that kind of you know
juicy juicy info and a lot of at first
glance you wouldn't see it CU you might
see the pages folder and see like you
know two things in there and nothing's
there that you haven't already seen But
if you you know go just one one step
further yeah 100% and and and I think JS
weasel is doing a lot of this stuff
right like doing the lazy loading you
know unpack it's an expensive tool but I
have seen a couple people give
testimonials recently saying like hey
this is really worth it finding a lot
more bugs with this yeah and I like it
and I and I I it's on my to-do list for
this week to go um and try it again and
work on it a little bit and you know see
if I can integrate into my workflow a
little bit more effectively yeah one
problem with that is it doesn't have
kaido integration and kaido is my main
tool that I'm using now for proxying I
switched over a couple weeks back and
I've put probably 80 to 120 hours in
kaido over the past three or four weeks
say I love everything about kaido except
for there's one thing and this has
always irked me and it's the scope
control like the way that that they
handle Scopes is like it has to be
basically like you have to know what the
domain is like the root domain in some
extent because it like on Burp you can
literally just put like word and it'll
just Rex like I I literally I literally
there's an open ticket they're going to
push it in I think probably the next
patch or maybe the patch after that but
I've told them like dude 90% of the time
I just want to give it a keyword and I
want to see you know S3 buckets that
have Facebook in it I want to see you
know uh tangental domains that have you
know the word Facebook in it or whatever
like that's the way to do it and and
it'll get there it'll get there and in
the meantime it's a little bit of a pain
but um yeah cuz I found like for example
I was I've also been trying to use kaido
significantly more as like my main tool
mainly just because the project like
honestly like I wish it was more than
this but the project switching is just
like a huge hassle in burp um the fact
that you can just like make a new
project and you can just switch through
it in the same window and all that it's
so nice um it's like a two-minute time
like I have like a crazy crazy strong
server that I use as my main you know
computer here 128 gigs of RAM top
processor I could get at the time it
still takes me like two minutes to
switch into burp projects right
literally three seconds I used to do
this this like really janky setup where
I would run multiple instances of burp
because this got so much this got on my
nerve so badly that I would run multiple
inces of burp and I would only like I
would have the proxy tab open and I
would just check uncheck the listen on
the other instances that I wasn't using
and then when I switch projects I would
like uncheck minimize bring up the other
instance turn the proxy on and just like
do it like that and just ignore all the
the warnings and whatever when you
launch with the temporary files and like
it's just it's just a pain so I've been
switching morido and uh that's like the
one thing that really that I miss is
that I was I was hacking on a scope for
example and I had their domain in there
and usually what I'll do is I'll do
percent. domain.com as well as
domain.com because that's another thing
that like you have to explicitly anyways
um and I was like doing a bunch of
hunting and sure enough I see in the DNS
logs like there's some completely
separate root domain that like had the
keyword in it but I didn't know it
existed and I was like oh [__] like
maybe I've been you know who knows maybe
I've been missing stuff on this so um
you know once they once they get that
added that'll be really awesome I do
like the idea of the the like the scope
control that they have but I think for
bug bounty hunting often it it needs to
be like just very Broad or just do a
full REX yeah just make you know default
please like yeah if you can't write Rex
you need to go fix that you know like
like there's so many bugs that happen
because of Rex hackers 90% of the time
should be able to write Rex all right
crazy side tangent here I when I first
started hacking I used to write in burp
full REX statements with like
conditional ores and like every
subdomain every everything thing in one
entry in my in my host in my like Target
config in burp and one time I was at a
live hacking event and chub saw me doing
that and he was like what are you doing
and I was
like I was like I'm adding this to the
scope he was like dude just put like
what just put like Facebook I was like
we we've always had we've all had that
moment with chubs anyone who's Met shubz
has been and you know he's kind as can
be about he's like hey man want to let
you know he like called Naf over he's
like
na like
he's like dude can you this guy's
writing full rexes for all his hosts I
was like wait doesn't everybody do this
no no Joel Only from I realized the
easiest way is just keyword and yeah
absolutely yeah yeah same same sort of
thing with when I first learned that you
could rename tabs oh oh by the way on
that note you know another thing about
kaido is that I've really been okay here
we
go back I'm going onto a tangent let's
do it though it's that kind of day on
the Pod um so going back to what we were
talking about before with notes I had
the opportunity to um uh screen share
with some hackers that I really respect
recently um and that take very deep
notes and um these hackers that I'm
talking about they're not using burp or
kaido or zap they're using
Postman and and it's because they're
coming from a Dev background right but
and and it
right yeah yeah and it and they're using
like um they're using what are they
using uh it's like Fiddler maybe I think
to get like as a proxy and then they'll
recreate it in Postman and I was like
okay that's ridiculous why would you do
that you know it takes so much time but
here's the thing
man the guy that I'm talking I'm
thinking of has like a whole collection
of like essentially built out API docs
for his Target with sample requests and
knows everything about it and it's he's
a he's a master of it you know like and
it's all organized you know all the tabs
have like get you know and then whatever
path you're doing is very easy to
navigate through and get the request you
need um and so big big fan of that I I I
definitely don't think that you need to
go as far as to use post man with it but
I've mentioned to kaido like hey it
would be really cool if we could provide
some sort of like um either even like an
llm prompt or like a u some sort of
configuration to auton our tabs and and
you know have them put into a certain
collection or something like that um
based off of where they are in the
application and that sort of thing and
just get a little bit more organized and
be able to use the collections a little
better and I'm actually getting to the
point now where I am using the
collections better in kaido um where I'm
creating you know certain collections
for gadgets for vules for interesting
requests I need to come back to for
specific chains that I'll need to do
like oh I'm going to chain this request
and this request and this request
together in that order so then I just
create a collection drop them all in
there boom boom boom that sort of thing
um so definitely some value in being a
little bit more organized with your
collections which I'm really
appreciative that kaido has in place
yeah for sure so I used to do a very
similar thing um I I use I don't use
Postman I I like Postman but I use a
tool called paw or well uh what's it
called now
um uh rapid API
but it's it's Mac only um so maybe
that's why post man but um it's
basically the same thing it you know it
lets you uh structure you know sort of
like like a developer really like you
can group your requests you can set up
different HTP requests they all have
like parameterized inputs um you know
it's it's made for like testing apis
really as a developer um but the the
really nice use case that I like to use
it for is when I have very complex htttp
requests that often require some sort of
crypto good example of this is ooth uh
hmac um I believe Twitter uses this I
think there's a couple other um things
that use it that I'm blanking on but
some sometimes they will use ooth hmac
in their authentication flow and it it
requires that you have to generate a
signature for every single request um
and and that it has to like have a token
that's like based on your current
request and has to be included in the
request and it's like you can't do it in
burp like in any easy way whatsoever you
could maybe script it in Python but
these tools often have extensions that
are designed exactly for this so you say
oh my o is oo here's my key here's my
secret done that's it like you just send
your request it automatically signs it
it automatically puts the token in it
automatically does all that kind of
stuff and in addition to that because
it's designed for apis you can often
structure it so for example you can use
variables uh I I assume you can probably
do this in Postman I'm not 100% familiar
but you can in in Rapid API where you
say you know within this project I have
a variable called let's say host name
right and then all of your requests you
just reference the variable host name
and then if you need to change that or
you wanna have staging environment you
let you want to test instead you just
change it in one place it changes it
everywhere um and so there there's
there's some really nice things that you
can do with the sort of like structured
side of that that the like developer
side of those testing tools that make it
really nice to test apis honestly the
only hassle with it is that you have to
kind of like rewrite it right so like
it's not as easy as just sending it to
your repeat Tab and just like editing
the path and sending it you have to
basically like clone it in
um there are importers I think in most
of these tools so like you can paste it
from like curl or you can paste it from
a raw HTTP request and it'll like parse
it out um but you know it's a little bit
of hassle but again for those cases
where it's like you know signing or hmac
and that kind of stuff it's really
really good for those that would be huge
in in burper kaido having the ability to
set a variable and say like okay this is
going to be my or ID always you know and
and just be able to reference that in
all of the requests and then have itace
almost hack verter esque right where
like it's kind of it's like hack verter
as a whole application where like it's
really designed around like you can have
gadgets you can like in Paw for example
like you can um you can wrap variables
in different functions and gadgets that
like modify that so you can like hex
encode or you can you know basic4 encode
or decode or like you can do all sorts
of different modifications on stuff like
on the Fly um that makes it really you
know really useful for those things
things that you could probably do to
some extent with hack bter um but
without an extension there's just no way
to do it in BT yeah and in kaido you can
do it with convert workflows uh if you
just select the whole request and then
send it to a convert workflow you shell
out and then do it in Python and then
replace it back or whatever uh you could
definitely make that work um uh so
that's interesting once kaido actually
implements the whole keep your workflows
across multiple projects thing I think
I'm going to I'm going to do that that
because that's the other big pain point
right now is that I have to redefine my
my convert stuff every uh for every
single project um but once they do that
I think I'll start doing a little bit
more tooling surrounding that sort of
thing um that would definitely be that
would definitely be huge and and I would
love to see that it also integrated with
a built-in sort of request minimizer
like they have in in in burp it's a burp
extension but uh something that just
breaks the request down to the Bare
Bones you know okay I know I need this
cookie I wanted to I wanted to like it
so bad but it never works for me what it
always works for me what do you mean it
doesn't work for whenever I use it it
always like gives me like it takes a
long time and then it gives me like a
weird output H that like doesn't that
doesn't work and so I end up just doing
it myself yeah I don't know maybe maybe
I'm doing it wrong but yeah it
definitely takes a long time I'll give
you that and you there's no feedback
because of how burp plugins are designed
you know but um I it always gives me a
good result and and uh yeah I guess you
need to make sure you're giving it the
base request right um with the expected
output as the response because the first
thing it's going to do is it's going to
send the request look at the output and
then it's going to remove everything
that still that results in anything
different than that output right um and
so yeah that's uh that's that's a cool
tool I would love to see that integrated
into kaido as well really looking
forward to when we get to plugins and
I'm able to sit down and like you know
code out all these plugins that I that I
need this is our chance Justin we could
we could be ahead of the market all they
have to do is monetize plugins and we're
we're billionaires oh true Man true yeah
like how the heck are we going to do
that hackers are going to be like just
go into the code and be like okay like
is licensed replace function return true
you know like it's that would be
terrible um one thing I did want to
mention before we get yeah too lost on
this tangent Charlie from JS weasel is
in the Discord and he's posted a couple
really useful like tips um um feature
updates um things that people didn't
really I saw he posted something about
being able to combine um the files that
it found everybody was like wait what
you could do that I didn't know there
was a thing um super cool so uh don't go
in there and pester him about problems
he said I think he even dropped an email
that um like I think it's support jelio
I want to say um but uh you know if you
have like problems just like send an
email because that's the best way for
them to track it but he's posting really
awesome stuff in there you know he's
letting people know about really cool
things so it's it's an awesome way to
interact with with Charlie from from JS
weasel if that's something you're
interested I know I know the kaido guys
as well are in there um and they also
have their own Discord which is super
like you know great place to they're
very responsive in there if you file
support tickets it's all like you know
they make it super easy um so yeah you
should check out their Discord too the
kaido Discord yeah 100% yeah they I've
been I've been pleased with yeah like I
mentioned xnl hacker is in there beex is
in there um speaking of beex
um dude awesome tool that will will um
yeah there was so so many cool
researches research things it's down a
little bit in the in the notes um I I
don't remember to he hon to be honest he
released it quite a while ago but I
don't think we've talked about it yet
because we had a couple episodes queued
to get us to the holidays but he
released this ssrf CVSs advisor.com
thing and I saw it before and if I
shouted it out you know it was in
passing I've used this extensively now
and it rocks um this is great
collaborator replacement for
collaborator yeah yeah yeah yeah I was
going to say um more and more dude I run
into the problem where my burp collab is
blocked uh because I just Ed the default
one and like it's such a hassle to set
up your own burp collab server like
unless you do it in the cloud where
there's no IP restrictions and like even
then like you often want a domain so
like it's a whole thing and like why
like why is this so hard like yeah yeah
yeah it's it's a real pin 100% And this
solves a lot of it and I kind of talked
about this before um actually I think I
sent out a tweet about it which is like
for any people building burp plugins
right now like
stop and and make it make it something a
little bit more generic make it make it
something that can be used uh you know
in kaido something that can be used in
burp something that can be used used in
Postman or whatever right um I really
like the the trend of having this you
know go in a different direction that's
why I really appreciate what what beex
did there um and it's got more features
and it's a you can Define your response
and that sort of thing which is really
cool one of the things that just came to
mind because of what you just said is I
wonder if he would be open to coding it
in such a way that you can Define your
own domain and then just point it at it
point it at the IP address right yeah I
just don't know how it does the like the
routing maybe it's all vhost or
something but it seem say this kind of
reminds me of like way back when bug
Bounty first started popping off in like
2017 2018 there was a big influx of tool
development where like dur Buster go go
search uh uh derb um yeah fuff like you
know all these like crazy crazy tools
just like popped out of the Woodworks
like got created out of necessity
and then things kind of died down a lot
of stuff got Consolidated into like the
proxy tools and whatever but now we're
seeing like we're kind of returning back
to fundamentals and it's nice to see
that like the community is sort of like
surging back and being like hey you know
like you could probably do this with
burp collaborator but if you want to do
it not with burp collaborator because
of need need I go back into all the
problems that people have with burp
collaborator you know you can do this
and I it reminds me like back in the day
there was a lot of tools that were like
this ping bin uh HTP bin um
there was a couple other ones yeah DNS
bin like there were always like separate
tools for like the different protocols
and stuff that were all just like online
tools you just like open it up it would
give you a random URL and you could just
use it as your payload it's pretty
functional you know yeah but a lot of
them are like dead now unfortunately so
it's nice that like we're kind of
Reviving it to some extent I don't know
if this if this srf testing uh tool is
only for HTTP and
https um yeah it is um and I'm not even
sure I'm not even sure it's for I
haven't used it for HTTP yet so I'm not
even sure that it supports HTTP but I'm
I'm really excited about the fact that I
need to hit pic up after this pod and
tell them hey man it would be great if
you could just like provide we could
provide our own domain pointing at that
IP address and have your own version
without any setup necessary right that
should be totally doable and then the
other thing is like I would love um the
one thing that this does ores or doesn't
do that collaborator does do couldn't
get that out um is that it it doesn't do
DNS right and DNS is huge um and it's a
pain in the butt to you know get it set
up sometimes you know I've talked before
about how easy it is to get it set up
with DNS chef but it's not as simple as
HTTP for sure um but I would love to see
that also sort of integrated into this
uh I could definitely see the community
really starting to get behind this
project as a as a primary um replacement
to collaborator if we could Define our
own domains and then also get DNS call
back that would be huge yeah yeah yeah I
mean this is basically like all those
tools that I was talking about earlier
like all those hdp based pingman DNS bin
htb bin whatever bin all in you know but
well this is really just htb right now
but hopefully we can you know get to
that all those other protocols and
everything too um and then maybe provide
it in a way that uh other people can can
mess with it too yeah 100% dude um we
are not even we we're not even halfway
done with the pre-episode so we're not
going to get to the full full episode
today um do you have time I have a
little bit of time okay all right all
right I'm G to keep I'm G to keep going
down talking about this cool stuff
though one thing that I wanted to share
that we mentioned on the on the Discord
and I realized wasn't really sort of
common knowledge for people is this sort
of concept of an iframe sandwich uh and
it's not really an iframe sandwich but
it's sort of like an open iframe
sandwich okay and and so uh this is
something that you can
cuz I've mentioned before on the Pod and
in other mediums that if you have a
Target that iframes in a subdomain okay
so let's say one of one of the the first
time I actually fully exploited this the
scenario was uh my target domain I
framed in a marketing subdomain where
you could control your email preferences
or whatever right okay not a huge impact
in that scenario but I did something
cool with it with ooth stuff and got ATL
um no big deal the yeah but um uh in
that scenario the iframe domain which is
different from the a different domain
from the primary domain if you can pop
an xss on that iframed domain you can do
some cool [__] okay so what you can do
is from an attacker and keep in mind
this domain is is iframed so normally it
has um you know iframe allow
configurations so what you can do from
your attacker control page you can
iframe in and do an invisible if frame
to that subdomain where you have the xss
pop the X SS get JS control okay then
from the attacker controlled page pop
open a new tab to the the victim domain
that you would like to attack and that
victim domain has the xss vulnerable
subdomain iframed in right and then what
you can do is you can reach from the if
frame on the attacker controlled page up
to the attacker page over to the the
victim domain and then down into the xss
domain um on that page by using
different frames and because you control
um js on the if frame on your page you
can modify the content of the iframe on
the victim domains page right that's
iframed into the victim domains page and
you can affect that content so let's say
in that scenario you can rewrite that
content with like you know uh something
that might could leak tokens something
that could you know you could put even a
uh you know sort of a fishing thing in
there and that sort of thing is is
normally accepted in my experience
because you're affecting the Integrity
of the inscope application by modifying
the contents of a domain that they are
iframing into their website um and and
so I kind of call this an iframe
sandwich it's not really you know when
iframes used to be a little bit more
permissive you could do some cooler
stuff with that but um just making sure
you understand how frames work and and
what kind of stuff you can access using
parent using opener using make sure
understand this yeah yeah on let's say
victim.com you have one tab open
victim.com inside it they have
vulnerable. comom yes yeah vulnerable.
comom or you know vulnerable. victim.com
or something like that okay sure and
vulnerable. victim.com is vulnerable to
an xss so now you get an xss you have an
xss inside an if frame on uh on Vic
well not exactly okay so let let me
break it down a little bit a little bit
better you've got your you've got two
frames or two pages two tabs with frames
in them okay okay one is an attacker
control or an attacker page and one of
them is the victim page both of them
have an if frame
to um exis has vulnerable domain right
okay using the ex you can't control the
the path in that is if framed into the
victim's domain so that's always going
to be iframed to wherever the victim
says it should go right okay but on the
attack controlled page you you can
control it so you pop xss through that
reach back up through the attacker
controlled page reach over to the the
tab that's opened up uh the other
iframed page reach into the iframe and
modify the content does that make sense
okay yeah so it's it's almost backwards
instead like you're modifying the the
victim page from the attacker page
exactly because it's the same iframe in
both of them because it's the same
origin yeah right same origin so you can
communicate with frames of the same
origin in a different tab is there a
better way to explain this because I I
had the same trouble well you explained
it from the other way around it was a
little confusing because it was kind of
like you get an xss within this ey frame
and then you set up your own P like I I
think the way you just described it now
is better where basically you have two
pages they both iframe the same URL you
have an xss in both of them but you can
easily pop it from your attacker page
which then you can use that context to
communicate with the context they
bothame you if frame they both if frame
the same domain but probably a different
URL if it's a reflected xss yeah you
know like there's no saying that like
maybe on victim.com right like that
you'd be able to actually pop it through
the URL or something maybe it's an
attack a complex attack scenario it
doesn't really matter because all you
need is control over that iframe context
with the same origin right yeah exactly
exactly and as long as you control
you're running JS execution right on
that on that origin and you have a path
to reach the the other frame right in
this scenario it would be
parent oh that's why you open it up from
the if
frame is that why you open it from
victim.com why you have to open it from
victim.com
no no no well you you have you have a
attacker controlled page with the with
the xss oh you just open the victim page
from your attacker page exactly that one
yeah and then you hop over there and
modify it um man maybe I should uh maybe
let me let me make a note here what
what we need a cardboard box diagam from
I'll I'll uh I'll draw a little draw a
diagram for if frame sandwich um I'll
draw a little diagram and put it on the
screen for those of you watching so
basically you you open attacker.com
attacker.com opens a new tab with
victim.com they both iframe the same URL
you pop the xss from your attacker.com
in in the if frame which can then
communicate with the if frame in the
other tab on victim.com and then you can
either control the content you can do
whatever you want within that I frame
exactly yeah and and and you know um
depending on the refer policy and stuff
like that you might be able to to leak
uh you know you uh ooth parameters and
that sort of thing um so all sorts of
cool stuff you can do with that it's a
good way to take an xss in a subdomain
that's you know maybe not even in scope
or less important and make it affect the
primary domain and increase your impact
um so these are the kind of things we're
discussing in in the uh in the ctbb
podcast Discord um so check it out CTB
.ow Discord hop on in enjoy that
conversation um all right so now we're
done with the pre-show an hour we in and
uh and now we can go into the news
section um so let's go ahead and let's
pop open these links and and we'll start
we already covered uh Beck's uh his
little his thing on um uh the ssrf tool
so that's good we got some work done um
first thing on the list
Yan Carlson um sort of retweeted a a
tweet that you guys really liked from
the critical thinking account talking
about a good open redirect um sort of
bypass to get to get open redirect and
he added a really um insightful piece of
information let me let me read that for
you there are some good and common ways
to gain redirects like at and Dot but
I've also had a lot of success with
double slash so SL slash a lot of simple
filters check if the URL is relative by
checking if it starts with a slash
forgetting that
slacker.com is not a relative domain uh
but is actually a uh an absolute URL um
and then he posts some examples down in
the bottom uh of sort of deviations on
this attack that have that use
backslashes they use Whit space that
sort of thing um and just really good to
be aware of these because sometimes if
you can bypass you know people make fun
of open redirect as a vulnerability but
sometimes if you can bypass redirect
logic it's a real problem so knowing
these tricks is really helpful ssrf 101
is like yeah yeah like check if it's in
the same domain okay well if you have an
open redirect and a lot of times it
follows redirects then game over yeah
and not even just ssrf but also it's
ooth 101 is like you know if you can
affect that redirect your
yeah in some scenarios S as well um if
you can affect that redirect URI then
you're golden um so definitely
definitely something to keep in mind
appreciate Johan uh hopping in there um
joining the conversation and adding
something uh really relevant there that
I've used a ton of times and just forgot
to include in that tweet yeah totally
yeah the double slash thing is a classic
I mean you see this a lot in browsers
legitimately too like script URLs often
use double slash um because I think
double slash is used to default to the
same protocol that the page uses right
exactly yep so if it's using HTTP it'll
use HTP if it's using htps it use htps
yep yep yeah yeah so really good uh
really good tip there yeah ni there was
a there was another tweet well actually
yeah it was a tweet um but also it was
posted somewhere within our hacker
circles um but the Google um bug Bounty
program vrp program vulnerability
Rewards program whatever you want to
call it um they released a burp sweep
plugin written in part by one of our
buddies Herby Sam um yeah and uh yeah
it's it's specifically for protuff
testing uh I think it's meant for Google
but you could probably use it for other
things it's a little bit narrow in terms
of how it works if you look into it cuz
I installed it and I was like why isn't
this working um it it looks for um
application prototo I think in in the
like in the response header but then it
will basically decode it and it will um
it'll make it easy so that you can
manipulate uh protuff requests without
having to have the Proto the Proto files
um and yeah it's it's really awesome um
I think there's like been a lot of
different tools that like kind of sort
of do similar stuff to this kind of um
but uh not not very well or not
completely and um yeah this is really
nice to see I have a solo episode about
protuff stuff that I still need to
record um and I'll probably include this
in there as well but yeah there's a
there's a lot of really interesting
stuff that you can do with protuff and
that you can use to figure out how
protuff is working yeah I was I was once
again you know the moat is disappearing
here you know I I was excited but also a
little sad to see them release this
because um Lupin and I mostly Lupin
really uh coded up an extension to do
this exact same thing probably with less
good results because Google actually has
a bunch of resources to allocate to it
like three Engineers were working on it
including Sam uh rather than just what
Lupin did late at night one night um but
uh you know we used this when we were
hacking Bard and we found a bunch of
grave bones with it um and and so
definitely increases the accessibility
of the Google vrp because one of the
biggest problems with hacking on Google
is you got to be a protuff g you know to
figure all that out um so really great
and I furthermore I think this is a
great example of how to be a good
program you know um if you build tools
specif specifically to help hackers hack
your program this takes a lot of work
because you have to be aware of how
hackers see your program right you have
to be aware of the problems they're
running into you pretty much have to
have tried to hack yourself right which
is something that so many companies
aren't even actually doing um and then
you have to take the initiative to get
some engineering done build out an
extension and then give it to the
community uh I I 100% sure that Google
will see a ton of Roi on their time for
building out this tool because it makes
it so much more approachable and I would
love to see companies that have insight
into their own architecture do similar
things to help promote their program
yeah absolutely um Joel Maris with
the yes yeah so no i' see like um I
think another good example of this is
like ssrf sheriffs for example like
stuff like stuff like that that just
show makes it easier tag on your program
especially you know Google has like
for for a very long time it felt like
Google had created a very complicated
stack that was hard to hack on and they
didn't really care about that and it was
not bad for overall security but you
know right but it's really security
through obscurity and it basically just
raised the bar for hacking it didn't
make
it more secure right and so I think by
doing this this helps bring the bar back
down a little bit so that it's easier to
start hacking on Google stuff and they
still get the security benefit of having
people look at their program and being
able to hack on it without like doing
you be like if you imagine like a new
person comes and like starts to hack on
some Google product that uses protuff
they're going to see this and be like I
have no idea what this is I literally
exactly what I did binary data I don't
know what a protuff is they go and look
up protuff it's some weird format they
don't understand the use case they don't
understand why it is or how it is or any
and they just give up they move on they
go to a different program they find
something that doesn't use it um and so
you need you need to do stuff like this
if you're going to be using it so
extensively and have such a a large
program if you want people to be able to
hack on your program you got to do stuff
like this yeah yeah yeah no I I I
totally agree creating those those means
to do that very very important
um let's let's see okay so I guess I'll
go ahead and pivot from here into
some js hoisting stuff you good with
that sure go for it I feel like I had
something else on that last topic that I
wanted to say but it escaped me so maybe
it'll come back later and and and I'll
I'll kind of go from there but um so I
tweeted out something it's funny to see
my own name in the dock here you know
under under the news section but I
tweeted something out which I thought
was worthy to talk about on the podcast
um because it's a pretty cool
exploitation scenario and we've been
having some chats like this a good bit
on Twitter
um uh just sort of surrounding various
xss SC areas we run into and a lot of
them have been brought to me by the
community the critical thinking
Community just dming me and being like
hey um I have a bug here but I can't
fully exploit it you know um and
sometimes I'll take a look sometimes I
won't no promises no promises but um
this time I did decide to take a look
and the scenario was this um we had an
injection uh so I'm I'm going down to
path of trying to represent things from
an audio perspective it's gonna be
tricky but okay let's say we had a fun
an injection at a place in the JS where
it was x.y where neither X nor y were
defined okay can you control them no you
can't control them they're they're not
defined and then it's it's it's a
function call so it's calling the
function x.y the first parameter is one
there's a comma and then you are
injecting okay and you can inject
anything you want except for script tag
you have to stay inside the script right
right um how do you get this to resolve
because as soon as it reads the line
it's going to say x is undefined uh you
know or Y is undefined can't access read
a property on undefined error and then
your code is never going to run um and
so I was looking at this I was like I
know that there's a way to exploit this
I can't figure out what it was and I
tried actually the solution that ended
up working but I was missing one stupid
little piece um and the answer to this
problem is something called J s hoting
have you heard of JS hoting Joel I don't
know if I've heard of the term but if
you explain it to me I might I might
have heard of it yeah so the term is JS
hoting and it's essentially the concept
that functions in JS defined using and
some other um objects as well but mostly
for this case functions defined using
the function
keyword despite where they are in the
flow will be hoisted to the top of the
of the script execution flow so so if
you define a function at the very bottom
using the function keyword of a script
tag and you call that function above
where that function is defined it'll
work because the function definition is
getting moved up to the top of um the
the script okay so in this scenario what
we were able to do was Define the
function X okay and uh and what that
would do is it would Hoist the
definition up to the top so now the
variable X now contains a valid function
Okay so so when you try to access the
property y on X you don't get an error
but you get Y is undefined then it will
attempt to call the the undefined uh y
because of the function call and when it
does that it will parse the parameters
that are being passed into that function
and at that point when it pars the
parameters you can do a function call in
the parameters themselves um and that
will get executed before it attempts to
call Y which will inevitably fail
because you can't call undefined
um and in that way we were able to get
arbitrary script execution and pop it
into an xss because of this concept
called JS hoisting so I wanted to shout
that out there because we're big fans of
of uh that kind of crazy Edge Fringe
JavaScript [__] here on the Pod um and
I'm not I wasn't even sure yeah I I I
feel like most people haven't heard of
it so I I would have been surprised if
you had heard of that
Joel yeah I was I was just testing some
things around he's got a he's got a
handheld mic and he's trying to type and
speak into the yeah I was testing some
things around this uh to see if there's
a better way and I think there might be
without having to break out
of the whole
thing all right this is like classic
Joel nerd sniped [__] right here okay
all right Joel reain it in reain it in
bring it back to the Pod okay what I was
going to say he says okay he's still
freaking looking at it I am still
freaking looking at it I was just gonna
not okay um yeah so the JS hoisting
thing it seems that so context is
important right um basically I thought
was like maybe you could do this without
having to break out of the function um
but even if you define X within the
parameters it doesn't work because it's
within the like so you can do it never
gets evaluated because it fails right in
the beginning right so like you you uh
tweeted out uh a similar like an excess
challenge like a while ago and it had to
do with essentially in JavaScript
there's a behavior where you can use
commas to provide multiple statements
and and you can assign variables to the
last variable the last thing that is
returned in that comma sequence um and
you can use that in a similar way here
um where you can use that for like you
know one comma what and you can just
within your parameters you can do the
same thing um but because it's within
that context of it's already trying to
call it it seems that it has to be like
what you said like you have to define it
because it's going to try and call it
before it evaluates um well it it's
going to try to read the the yeah like
the object itself so it's going to does
object exist then it gets the parameters
then it passes them into the function
call exactly and when it tries to say
hey I need to get the x or the Y
property of x then and X is undefined
then you can't get a property of
undefined and then that'll error right
um so shout out to bit k um and to Johan
and a couple of the other people that I
think Carl also Carell origin um also
got it um and was able to to exploit
this so uh definitely appreciate the the
help there and I learned a lot about
JavaScript that day because then I had
to deep of course I had to Deep dive JS
hoisting so there's a bunch of um you
can do it with variables you can do it
with classes but the cool thing about
functions is it's not just
um the thing doesn't just get defined it
gets sort of it's initialized to it's an
actual object I'm pretty sure the
reasoning for this was that like way
back in the day there was a there was a
historical problem with programming
languages where if you define something
after it was used it couldn't be called
and I think this is most common with
like C and C++ and stuff but if you had
a function that was like if your main
function essentially wasn't at the end
of your program then you couldn't like
call anything else because it didn't
know it existed I think this was maybe
why header files ex I don't know I'm I'm
not an expert on this but essentially
like that's part of what JS is trying to
solve here is that like if you call
something before it's defined it should
still be able to call it even if because
it's defined it's just that like it it
does some restructuring and like I don't
know yeah it's super interesting um well
reing that existing Behavior to to work
in in your in your favor yeah the the
other interesting thing with this is
that um it doesn't it doesn't work for
variables def find to functions so for
example if you did VAR x equals function
blah blah blah blah and defined it that
way like you're defining a variable
point into a function rather than using
the function keyword then it won't work
but if you use the function keyword um
as the primary expression in that that
line of code then um it will it will
hoist it so lots of cool lots of cool
things there I was just talking to my my
brother-in-law the other day who's a
programmer and we were talking he was
saying he freaking hates JavaScript and
I was like man I love JavaScript because
JavaScript there's so many ways to get
everything done and there's so many
quirks to the language it's like a dream
it really is so it really is yeah it's
super interesting that um if you define
it as a variable it works but doesn't
work what do you mean so when you when
you do like if you do varx equals
function afterwards after the call yeah
it'll say cannot read properties of oh
no it doesn't work sorry I misread I
misre it my bad Sor well sometimes it'll
so there is something you can do with
VAR because VAR will Hoist the the def
defin to the top or the um
initialization no not that the
definition to the top but not the
initialization there we go um or maybe
it's the Declaration that's what I'm
looking for it it'll Hoist the
Declaration but it will not Hoist the
initialization um and so that's a little
bit of a of a quirky thing there all
right Joel um so before we get further
nerd sniped on this let's move to the
next thing because actually as far as
nerd soping goes I was just kind of
researching this this this morning on a
whim and I am just I just love CSP
bypass [__] dude I don't know why it
just feels great um and this is so cool
once again our boy Johan is just
dropping all sorts of amazing [__] this
one was actually in the um the cool
research uh channel on the on the
Discord which is a gold mine of cool
research I'm so glad we built that
channel I've been reading everything
that comes through there and I've seen
so many things that I've missed somehow
um so really appreciate everyone
contributing to that one of the things
that dropped in there was this crazy uh
yeah it's the first one uh Joel
octagon.svg
in the specific example it's using
Wordpress a WordPress endpoint that has
Json P compatibility right so you can
bypass CSP on on a WordPress site y this
one is so cool what what but the the the
Json P endpoint that's there it doesn't
allow you to use commas it doesn't allow
you to use things so it's a secure Json
PN point it doesn't allow you to write
your own code essentially in the call
back right it just allows you to use
dots and letters which is what you see
with a lot of fixed Json PN points they
don't want you to be able to write alert
you know Open Bracket close bracket and
then just be able to run arbitrary code
there but he this guy figured out a way
to actually use this still to bypass CSP
okay so essentially what what he figured
out how to do was um so in a Json PM
point it obviously it's going to call
the function with its own contents at
the end of the day uh here Joel let me
um let me actually send you um I can
send
you uh the actual endpoint really
quickly here so you have an example of
what I'm looking at um um hold on just a
sec I want I want you to be able to see
this because it's just
so okay so here's an example of the
actual I'm going to send it to you on on
uh I'm going to put it in the the
Riverside chat because it's it's uh I've
got Discord closed so it doesn't I was G
to say I also did reopened it there um
do you see that I do see that okay so go
to that go to that URL so you see how it
says uh attacker input and it's got the
function call and then the data inside
of it right this classic Json P um call
back okay um what he does here is
instead he so we can only inject
characters and and dots he builds out
this flow okay let me see if I can find
it it says
um so you can open wind you can do
window. opener do whatever and then
select a uh button on the parent tab
right via that and then call the click
function with that and it doesn't matter
the context right and then what you're
going to have to do you're going to have
to open this page up uh via a a window.
openen from your attacker control page
right now it's open two separate frames
redirect the attacker controlled page to
a the target domain where you have a
button that you want to get clicked
right like delete account okay so now
the two pages the two tabs that are open
are same origin
right and then what you do is you
trigger the xss and it will go back to
window. opener when it when it calls the
the the xss this is this is same origin
now so it can reach back up through
window. opener and call the do click
function on a specific button that you
want like delete account right so you
can actually weaponize this to reach
back up to the different Tab and Trigger
it w with just the use of you know
window. open
body first element sibling you know
Define that whole flow out that same
kind of where from attacker page you
open the victim page and then you're
going cross tab using the same origin to
abuse Behavior within the page similar
concept to what we were talking about
earlier but a little bit different
because after you open the tab with the
attacker um you know from the attacker
controled page you remove the attacker
controlled context from you you you you
know piece out of there you redirect
that that opener to or you redirect
Yourself by the way it behaves it you
know yeah yeah and then window. opener
still points back to that frame which is
so cool I guess that makes sense yeah
because it's the same it's like the same
tab instance or whatever yeah they're in
the same sort of tab group and window.
opener is pointing back to that frame
but now that frame is same origin and so
you're not going to get an error if you
try to execute window. opener. content
document do you know body. child. child.
child. click right and then it'll just
call that function with the CSP bypass
click on the button and cause
essentially a c surf to happen
um is that not absolutely breathtaking
it's a really interesting exploit I I I
love that kind of creativity where you
know we've talked about this before but
browsers are adding a lot of security
features that make it very difficult to
exploit um even like if something's
vulnerable it's difficult to exploit it
um like you can see the vulnerability
but it's just difficult like just due to
security mechanisms in place and these
new types of attacks that are coming out
now a lot of them are utilizing even
within that secure environment they're
utilizing just like Baseline behavior in
order to abuse it in order to make it do
stuff that you want like click buttons
um like it's almost like a whole new
csrf in a sense yeah I mean same thing
that's happening that I rant about all
the time with client side path
traversals um yeah stage
and yeah yeah these these new sort of um
Frontier of vulnerabilities are coming
forth and it's really exciting um it's
very hard for me to be honest I'm
surprised you got it Joel um it's very
hard for me to do this
vulnerability um Justice uh over the a
audio medium because you really need to
be able to kind of see what is happening
um so I'm definitely going to link this
one if you're going to read anything
that we did today well if you're going
to if you're going to do anything that
we have talked about today join the ctbb
podcast Discord because this stuff pops
up there but if you're going to do two
things the second thing should be uh
octagon.svg
trigger that functionality within the
within the confines of CSP super
inspiring um super cool yeah really love
that uh and and it's those Json P
gadgets are actually everywhere you know
a Json P Gadget that allows you to
actually AR run arbitrary code um those
are those are still there but they're
disappearing these are everywhere um and
so really cool to see someone actually
be able to exploit that yeah totally I
mean
the CSP bypass tool is always like you
know oh Json p and there was just this
discussion about this too where people
were like I I don't really see J Json P
use very much and you were like actually
I see it all the time I justed recently
yeah so much Legacy stuff in there and
and especially if people like will star
their own domain in if they have a uh
you know a Blog every company has a Blog
on their main domain right that uses
WordPress there's WordPress endpoints
that use Json P just like this and you
run arbitrary code but using this you
can actually get a c surf with your you
know sort of half xss and this will also
help prove that there's impact to xsss
that are blocked by CSP in a lot of
cases as well um it just takes time and
dedication to actually break through it
so um on on the on that note um another
one of my favorite pieces of research uh
released in 2018 by
wallarm uh wall wallarm w a l l a r m um
um when I first saw this I was like wow
this is so genius and I figured it'd be
fitting here because we're already
talking about
CSP um this is a scenario where you have
xss and you're able to execute you know
your alert because unsafe in line is
allowed on the CSP
policy
um but you can't run arbitrary code
either because of a length limitation or
um because you the CSP prevents you from
reaching out to another domain in any
way and you can't really xill anything
besides maybe like a a page redirection
or something like that which might mess
up your your flow of the attack this is
a really cool bypass that uses sort of
proxying of sorts to bypass ESP and so
the scenario is you've got a Content uh
security policy with unsafe in line
allowed and you want to xfill data um
and what you do is you write a script
which will iframe in another page on
that same domain so once again we're
same origin we're abusing origin related
stuff here you can reach into that
iframe control the content um and you
look for a page like a CSS file or a JS
file or a PNG file any sort of file that
does not have the content security
policy header and every time I've looked
for that I found it because people use
these you know reverse proxies nowadays
where they're like reaching into you
know an S3 bucket to store their assets
and that sort of thing everyone's doing
this and the CSP header is really not
globally defined across the whole scope
um and when it's not you can use that
non CSP header having page as a proxy
for communication out so you iframe in
that page and then you can control the
uh script execution on that iframe in
page and that page does not have CSP
limitations and so then you can use that
to arbitrarily grab content that you
want to load from uh you know your your
your website pull it down and then
execute it on the parent context as well
because once again same Origins we can
you know load a script on that page so
in this scenario you're basically you're
using let's say reflected xss in line on
on the victim domain to
iframe a same origin domain on the
victim that is missing CSP for yeah
something and then you use your xss to
change the contents of that frame to
load to include a script from
location right and because it has no CSP
in the frame then you can include an
attacker script which has free access to
do whatever it wants and the parent
frame because the same origin yeah and
that can xfill data it can load
arbitrary scripts that sort of thing you
know a lot of times when you're trying
to um show impact for an xss they say
hey please prove arbitrary um uh
execution of JS right not just alert
show me that you can run any script
right um how do you usually show that
um so for me you know a lot of times if
you can pull from a domain that's great
but a lot of times when they're asking
for this it's in a length limited
context right where you would have a
hard time fetching data and X filling it
right um but uh in in a scenario like
this um break out because you can
include your yeah exactly and then as
soon as you include that script inside
the child uh tag uh or the child if
frame then you're loading from a domain
and then you've got all the all the JS
execution you need to do multi-step
attack um and really xfill some
important data and and you can also do
it blindly right you don't need the
victim doesn't need to know that that's
happening um uh and and so really cool
way to bypass the SP from wallarm um
we'll link that that uh technique down
in the in the show notes um find that a
lot of this iframe stuff is harder to do
with with the x-frame option stuff
nowadays it most certainly is yeah but
the cool thing thing about this though
is that if it's missing the CSP header
it's probably also missing the x-frame
options header because those are
normally grouped in the same sort of um
reverse proxy header appending rule um
so I I still see this from time to time
and actually a technique like this not
exactly like this but um but similar to
this helped me score a 70k xss one time
um and it was a heck of a a bug um
xss it was D It's Crazy to me that my
highest Bounty is in xss but uh it was
affecting I mean it was it was a company
where the client side is everything you
know yeah um and where they really have
to keep their client side tight and if
they if they make a problem it affects a
ton of people um so really really uh
excited to make sure people know about
this technique as well because it's it's
near and tear to my heart yeah that's
awesome all right we are
what we're like an hour and a half in an
hour and a half we just made it through
the news so we probably call it here
yeah we should call it here I'm just
going to say this for those of you um
and and we we'll cover a little bit more
in the future as well on this but um
open ID and oath
stuff extremely
interesting impact is
everywhere there's a lot of standardized
endpoints from the uh open ID standard
uh that will will allow you to do a lot
better Recon on your targets and try to
get access to areas of the applications
that you may not have access to you
because of permissioning problems um by
knowing open ID really well so um
hopefully we'll deliver you some content
in the future diving into that a little
bit deeper but for now just know that
that is coming because we'll we'll you
know do some reading on it beforehand I
see what youres on I see what your
curses on and you you just left them
with quite a teaser I I I did man I did
there's some there's some great stuff
there and you know I I will
say I'll be the first to say that doing
a podcast on an extremely
technical field is extremely challenging
and I think I'm probably subpar at
taking extremely technical content and
condensing it into just words and
conveying that picture to The Listener
in a way that that is easily
comprehensible that's something that I'm
working on but um if you guys actually
do the homework after the episodes and
maybe even before the episodes when I
give you a heads up like this the stuff
that I'm talking about will start making
a lot more sense um and you'll get a lot
more really not not not clear what I'd
recommend is go to the show notes open
the link that we're talking about and
side like either side by side or in your
in your headphones listen to us talk
about it as you're reading through the
article and it'll probably make
significantly more sense because that's
a lot of what we do as well as we have
them both open as we talk about it so um
we're talking about Concepts that might
might not be clear um like verbally
we're not great at explaining it but
then if you just read through it you'll
it'll make sense yeah 100% And I think
Joel as well you you do a good job of
sort of teasing it out and and making me
re-explain it and re simplifying the
words once I is because like you you you
T the way you approach things often is
like from the Hacker's perspective and
this this is a common mistake as well
like report writing this happens all the
time where hackers like explain stuff
from a hacker pers perspective instead
of from like a fresh perspective and uh
you have like a lot of like side data in
there that like makes sense to you but
doesn't make sense to anybody else so
you have to like it it's difficult it's
a skill for sure well I'm glad I brought
a program manager on as well to to help
me get this uh you know sort of context
included I'm solid Life Choices getting
you on this SP Joel I love you man
awesome all right cool well that that's
wrap yeah yeah that's the W all right
that's the Pod
peace